Cobb Family Papers
Cobb Family Papers
1823-1968
Cobb family.
22.5 linear ft.
Several generations of an important New England family. Clippings, correspondence, subject file, manuscripts, printed material, journals, photos, scrapbooks, books, artifacts, sermons, articles, correspondence, diaries, calendars, notebooks, more.
2810822
Biographical History
The Cobb family was a large and important New England clan (see Philip Cobb's A History of the Cobb Family, Cleveland:1907). The main branch of the Cobb family descended from Ebenezer and Elizabeth Cobb, both of whom were descended from Elder Henry Cobb who arrived in America on the second voyage of the Mayflower. One of their eight children, Sylvanus, was born in 1798 and grew up in Norway, Maine, and it is his branch of the family that is represented in this collection.
As a young man Sylvanus showed an aptitude for journalism, and wrote poetry and prose for the Republican war party of 1812. At sixteen he converted to the Universalist faith and a few years later studied for the ministry under Sebastian Streeter. After his ordination he traveled across Maine, preaching the Universalist doctrine. Because his views opposed the Calvinist doctrine of predestination, he met with considerable hostility and was attacked in the press. He was also active in politics and served two terms in the state legislature.
In 1828, amid controversy and protest, Sylvanus became pastor of the First Unitarian Universalist Church of Malden, Massachusetts. Shortly after his installment he was elected to the Massachusetts legislature where he made the acquaintance of many important politicians, including Leverett Saltonstall. This did not prevent him from pursuing his primary calling as a clergyman, and his influence within the Universalist movement continued to grow. As his reputation expanded he developed friendships with most of the major figures in the movement, especially Hosea Ballou. He attended, and was one of the leaders of, the Universalist General Conventions, speaking out vigorously in many of the debates. In 1839, while living in East Boston, he founded the newspaper Christian Freeman and Family Visitor, which under his editorship supported such causes as abolition, temperance, and of course the Universalist movement. Some of the greatest debates of the era between orthodox Calvinists and Universalists were carried on in the pages of the Freeman. Sylvanus also wrote several books, of which Compend Divinity and New Testament of Our Lord and Savior were the most significant.
Sylvanus Cobb Jr. was the eldest son of Sylvanus and his wife, Eunice Hale Waite, born in 1823. As a young man he joined the Navy, and during his service he traveled throughout Europe, building a storehouse of knowledge that would serve him well in his later career as a novelist. Soon after his marriage in 1845, he began to write short stories for his own newspaper, Rechabile, which was notable for its attacks (in the name of temperance) on President Polk, Daniel Webster and others. Later he wrote for Robert Bonner's New York Ledger. He became one of the most prolific fiction writers of his time.
On August 6, 1834, twin boys were born to Sylvanus and Eunice. Darius and Cyrus grew up in the family home near Boston and studied art, music and literature, becoming skilled enough artists that they eventually started their own portrait business. After brief service during the Civil War with the 44th Massachusetts regiment, the two men returned home and married sisters Laura and Emma Lillie. The two men took up art again, Darius concentrating on painting and Cyrus on sculpture. In time Cyrus became a lawyer with the intention of supporting his brother's artistic endeavors. After ten years as an attorney Cyrus again took up art but, although he achieved some success (most notably with his design and execution of the Cambridge Soldiers' Monument), Darius became far better known. John Greenleaf Whitter judged his painting "Christ Before Pilate" to be "the best ideal of Divine Humanity I have ever seen" and Henry Wadsworth Longfellow -- a personal friend -- headed a list of subscribers for steel plate engravings of the work. Darius also became known for his portraiture and historical pieces, particularly "Washington at Dorchester Heights."
Both twins had large families and several of their children became famous. Ernest Cobb, son of Cyrus, was a well-known educator and the author of a number of children's books, as well as One Foot on the Ground, a plea for reconsideration of the Progressive Education method. Stanwood, son of Darius, was valedictorian of his class at Dartmouth and studied at Harvard Divinity School. As a young man he traveled in Europe with Porter Sargent's Travel School for Boys, and taught at Robet College in Constantinople. Out of his experiences in Turkey grew a lifelong interest in the Near East, particularly in the Baha'i religion, which he espoused. In 1919 he founded the Chevy Chase Country Day School in Maryland and the Progressive Education Association; he became editor of a major Baha'i publication and the author of numerous books on Baha'i, mysticism, the Near East, and education.
A family tree of the Cobb family is available here (if online) or at the end of this inventory (if in hard copy). Names given in capital letters signify individuals with related material in the collection.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Cobb Family Papers consist of materials created by various members of one small branch of a very large and important New England family, and offer a window into both their careers and private lives. The papers provide valuable information on Universalism, Progressive Education, Baha'i, and the cultural history of Boston during the 19th and early 20th centuries. Span dates for the collection are 1823-1968, with the heaviest concentration in the period 1850-1955, when the main branch of the family resided in Massachusetts.
The majority of the papers relate to Stanwood Cobb and his activities as author and educator. There are also substantial sections associated with Stanwood's father Darius Cobb, a popular Boston artist, and his grandfather Sylvanus Cobb Sr., Universalist clergyman, author, and editor-publisher of his own newspaper, Christian Freeman and Family Visitor. The extensive diaries kept by Sylvanus Cobb Sr. and Darius Cobb are perhaps the most important part of the collection, of interest to cultural historians of Boston as well as to students of the history of education or religion. Other Cobb family members represented include Sylvanus Jr., Ernest, Eunice Hale Waite, and Percival B. Cobb.
The papers are divided into five sections, as follows.
The six boxes of Correspondence span more than 140 years and a wide range of topics from family matters to religion and politics.
Drawings and related material contains original artwork and sketches by Darius Cobb and his twin brother Cyrus.
Financial and legal records consists of account books, lists of subscribers for Darius' paintings, several books belonging to Stanwood Cobb recording college and other expenses, and a variety of legal documents such as mortgages and agreements.
Memorabilia, subdivided by individual, encompasses a vast range of material including clippings, Bahai material, college catalogs, diaries, drawings, genealogies, invitations, lecture notes, obituaries, photographs, and a small group of French periodicals and pamphlets.
Writings, also subdivided by individual, includes articles, books, essays, sermons, speeches and more. The bulk of this section is comprised of Stanwood Cobb's writings on Progressive Education, Bahai, social criticism, and literary subjects. Other significant items include Darius Cobb's diaries, which span more than sixty years, and his fiction and non-fiction writings.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is in chronological order. For the other series, other than their alphabetical subdivision by individual family member, there is no discernible order.
Subject and Genre Headings
Cobb, Cora, 1868-1960.; Cobb, Cyrus, 1834-1903.; Cobb, Darius, 1834-1919.; Cobb, Eunice Hale, 1803-1880.; Cobb, Laura Lillie, 1846-1919.; Cobb, Stanwood, 1881-1982.; Cobb, Sylvanus, 1798-1866.; Cobb, Sylvanus, 1823-1887.; Cobb family.; Grand Army of the Republic.; Progressive Education Association (U.S.); Unitarian Universalist churches -- Clergy.; Christian freeman and family visiter.; Antislavery movements -- United States.; Artists -- United States -- 19th century.; Bahai Faith -- History -- 19th century.; Capital punishment -- United States.; Clergy as authors.; Painting, American -- 19th century.; Progressive education.; Temperance -- Addresses, essays, lectures.; Boston (Mass.) -- History.; Account books.; Autobiographies (literary works); Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts); Diaries.; Drawings (visual works); Essays.; Genealogies (histories); Manuscripts for publication.; Obituaries.; Photographs.; Poems.; Sermons.; Sketchbooks.; Speeches (documents); Lectures.; Artists.; Authors.; Clergymen.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Stanwood Cobb, 1964-1969.
Additions, unspecified, 1971-1972.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous undated (Box 1)
  - Fragments, 1903-1927 (Box 1)
  - General, Jan 1823-Sep 1901; 18 folders (Box 1)
  - General, Oct 1901-Dec 1907; 11 folders (Box 2)
  - General, 1908-1913; 11 folders (Box 3)
  - General, 1914-1924; 15 folders (Box 4)
  - General, 1925-1963; 18 folders (Box 5)
  - General, 1964-1968; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, 1922 (Box 41)
    Restricted due to condition. Use photocopy filed in the appropriate location in Box 4.
- Drawings and related material
  - Cyrus Cobb
    - Original drawing (Box 7)
    - Reproduction of original, 1899 (Box 7)
    - Sculptures and paintings in which Cyrus and Darius shared (Box 7)
    - Critiques of paintings by Darius, 1880-1900 (Box 7)
  - Darius Cobb
    - Original drawings, 1854-1916; undated; 4 folders (Box 7)
    - Reproductions of originals, 1890-1914; 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Sketchbooks, 1882-1883; 6 volumes (Box 7)
- Financial and legal records
  - Financial records, miscellaneous, 1896-1912 (Box 7)
  - Account books, miscellaneous, 1905-1919; 3 volumes (Box 7)
  - List of subscriptions for paintings by Darius (Box 7)
  - Stanwood Cobb
    - Financial records, miscellaneous, 1923-1937 (Box 7)
    - Account books of college expenses, 1900-1903; 2 volumes (Box 7)
    - Account book of minor expenses, 1903 (Box 8)
    - Account books of summer earnings and expenses, 1899; 2 volumes (Box 8)
    - Order forms, 1932 (Box 8)
  - Cobb, C. vs Buchleg, D.A., 1890; lawsuit, dismissed (Box 8)
  - Cobb, C. and Cobb, A., 1902; agreement (Box 8)
  - Cobb, C. and Cobb, D., 1895; mortgage (Box 8)
  - Cobb, C. and Recchia, F., 1900; agreement (Box 8)
  - Cobb, C. and Cobb, D., 1894; agreement (Box 8)
  - Cobb, Stanwood, 1910; safe conduct for travel in Turkey (Box 8)
  - Cobb, Stanwood, unidentifed document in Arabic (Box 8)
  - Marcy, H.O. and Cobb, Cyrus, 1895; agreement (Box 8)
  - Mills, S.A. and Cobb, Cyrus, 1899; agreement (Box 8)
  - Wilcox, J. and Cobb, C. and D., 1879; agreement (Box 8)
- Memorabilia
  - Cobb, Cora
    - Clippings, 1909-1959 (Box 9)
    - Darius and Cyrus biography (Box 9)
    - Darius and Cyrus biography, clippings, 1899-1951 (Box 9)
    - Biography of D., told by Cora C., 1960 (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Darius
    - Invitation to White House reception (Box 9)
    - Obituary, 1919 (Box 9)
    - Tributes to an artist and his work, 1913 (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Ida
    - Obituary, 1919 (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Laura Lillie
    - Drawings and exercise books, 1860; 4 volumes (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Lillie
    - Clippings, 1906 (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Percival B.
    - Program, "Re-ordination of Percival B. Cobb", 1914 (Box 9)
  - Cobb, Stanwood
    - Cartoon original by C.K. Berryman, to S.C., 1940 (Box 9)
    - Summaries of books by S.C., 1899 (Box 9)
    - Translation of Arabic poem (Box 9)
    - Plan for a daily calendar (Box 9)
    - Copy of illuminated manuscript, 1908 (Box 9)
    - Numerological chart for life of S.C., 1924 (Box 9)
    - Spirit messages (Box 9)
    - Harvard knitting mill, 1905 (Box 9)
    - Appointment notebook, 1905; 2 volumes (Box 9)
    - Biography association with McCall family, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Biography association with Potter Sargent and Elihu Vedder, S.C., 1967 (Box 9)
    - Biography clippings, 1903-1968 (Box 9)
    - Letters of recommendation, 1967 (Box 9)
    - Marriage certificate, 1919 (Box 9)
    - Medical records, 1929 (Box 9)
    - Notebooks, 1907 (Box 9)
    - Notebook for teaching English Comp., Hobart College, 1908 (Box 10)
    - Lecture notes (Box 10)
      - Discussion of style, 1904 (Box 10)
      - Philosophy, Dartmouth, 1903 (Box 10)
      - History of Religion, Harvard, 1906; 4 folders (Box 10)
      - Newton High School, 1898-1899 (Box 10)
    - Notebooks, miscellaneous, 1902; 2 volumes (Box 10)
    - Notebooks, college, 1902-1903; 3 volumes (Box 11)
    - Report card, Newton High, 1898-1899 (Box 11)
    - Scrapbook of Europe trip, annotated, 1910-1913 (Box 11)
    - Unidentified silhouette (Box 11)
  - Cobb, Sylvanus Jr.
    - "Uncle Seth and the Modern Novel Poem", 1913 (Box 11)
    - Genealogies for family of Sylvanus and Eunice Cobb (Box 11)
    - History and lists re: formation of the Washington Authors Club, 1936-1965 (Box 11)
  - Photographs (Box 11)
    - Unidentified children, 1880-1920; 2 folders (Box 11)
    - Cobb, Cora, 1895-1900 (Box 11)
    - Cobb, Darius and Cyrus, 1850-1870 (Box 11)
    - Cobb, Darius and Cyrus, 1883 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Darius, 1850; 1860-1919; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Darius, 1914; group family photo (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Edith, 1890-1905 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Ernest, 1910 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Estella, 1900 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Eunice Waile, 1860-1870 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Fredrich W., 1905 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Ida, 1910-1930 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Laura Lillie, 1860-1916 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Lillie, 1890-1960 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Percival B., 1885-1938 (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Stanwood, 1898-1968; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Stanwood, 1912; album (Box 12)
    - Cobb, Stanwood, 1910-1912; trips to Europe (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Stanwood, Chevy Chase and Newtown, Mass. (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Stanwood, Greece (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Stanwood, 1912; reproduction of Turkey (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Sylvanus, 1854 (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Sylvanus, 1850; group family photo (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Sylvanus Jr., 1885 (Box 13)
    - Cobb, Walter, 1890 (Box 13)
    - Cobb, assorted distant relatives, 1920-1957 (Box 13)
    - Frost, Robert, 1932 (Box 13)
    - Lillie, Harriet M., 1880 (Box 13)
    - Meyers, Robert, 1928 (Box 13)
    - Powell, John, 1914; autographed (Box 13)
    - Richardson, Captain Spencer, 1863 (Box 13)
  - Cobb family, miscellaneous
    - Articles and booklets, miscellaneous, 1923 (Box 13)
    - Clippings, miscellaneous, 1919-1961 (Box 13)
    - Baha-i material, 1908-1933; pamphlets, booklets, etc. (Box 13)
    - Chevy Chase school, 1919; announcements, brochures, programs (Box 13)
    - Chevy Chase school, 1903; commencement booklets (Box 13)
    - Brochures, advertisements in books by Stanwood C. (Box 13)
    - Coonley, Queene and Charlotte Drum, Great Thoughts, 1954; book (Box 13)
    - DeCroly and Boon, "Veis l'ecole renovee", 1921 (Box 13)
    - Dalhem, Louis, Contribution a l'introduction de la Methode DeCroly, 1923 (Box 13)
    - Fowler, O.S., Synopsis of Phrenology and Phrenological Developments, 1838 (Box 13)
    - Catalogs
      - The Female Institute, Oaksville, 1828 (Box 13)
      - Progressive Education Association, 1919-1923 (Box 13)
      - The Norway Institute, 1849 (Box 13)
      - Hobart College, 1912 (Box 13)
      - Hobart College, 1924 (Box 13)
      - St. John's College, 1913-1914 (Box 14)
    - Columbia University, 1934; report of the Secretary of Appointment (Box 14)
    - Dartmouth
      - Class bulletin, 1903 (Box 14)
      - Class of 1903 reunion, 1938 (Box 14)
      - "The Daily Dartmouth", 1903 (Box 14)
      - Clippings, Dr. Tuchor, 1903 (Box 14)
    - Educational material, 1928-1935 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Grand Army of the Republic, 1907-1910; rosters and booklets (Box 14)
    - Lecture by Darius C., 1915 (Box 14)
    - Lecture by Stanwood C. (Box 14)
    - Literary Society, 1954 (Box 14)
    - French periodicals and pamphlets
      - L'experience de l'ecole des roches et la reforme de l'education en France (Box 14)
      - "Methode DeCroly", 1922 (Box 14)
      - "La nouvelle education", 1927-1932 (Box 14)
      - "Pour l'etre nouvelle", 1928 (Box 14)
      - "Les problemes de la psychologique genetique", 1923 (Box 14)
      - "Le reform de l'education nationale et l'ecole de roches", 1920 (Box 14)
    - Periodicals
      - The Baha'i Magazine, 1926 (Box 14)
      - The Layman's Movement, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
      - The Revolation, Stanwood C., 1898 (Box 14)
      - The Newton High School Review, 1898-1899; 11 folders (Box 14)
- Writings
  - Behenna, K. Arthur
    - Mystic Songs of Flame and Fire, 1921 (Box 15)
  - Carrel, Alexis
    - "Dragon is Power" (Box 15)
  - Cobb, Cora
    - God's Wonder World, 1918 (Box 15)
  - Cobb, Cyrus
    - Diary, 1877-1880 (Box 15)
    - "Adventure with Robber Ghost-Makers", 1860 (Box 15)
    - "Night Adventure in a Hermit's Cavern", 1885 (Box 15)
    - "By Penobscot Bay", poem (Box 15)
  - Cobb, Darius
    - "Art as study", 1895 (Box 15)
    - "Experience with savage dogs", 1905 (Box 15)
    - "Reminiscences of George Innes", 1963; reprint (Box 15)
    - Untitled (Box 15)
    - Autobiography inputs, 1912; 1917; 2 volumes (Box 15)
    - "Adeline Desmond or the Spy of Newbern", 1863 (Box 15A)
    - Unidentified novel, 2 folders (Box 15A)
    - Diaries, 1852-1854 (Box 15A)
    - Diaries, 1854-1865; 6 volumes (Box 16)
    - Diaries, 1866-1881; 4 volumes (Box 17)
    - Diaries, 1881-1907; 4 volumes (Box 18)
    - Diaries, 1907-1919; 2 volumes (Box 19)
    - Diary notes, 1879 (Box 19)
    - Hymn lyrics, 1900 (Box 19)
    - Song lyrics, Darius and Cyrus reunion, 44th Mass. Volunteers, 1890 (Box 19)
    - Pamphlets, "The Master" and "The Mission of the Master", 1914 (Box 19)
    - "The Story of the Picture at the Tuileries Painted by Darius Cobb", 1900 (Box 19)
    - Speeches (sermons)
      - "The Kingdom of God is Within You", 1877 (Box 19)
      - "The Vitalizing Power of the Sacred Element in Art", 1877 (Box 19)
    - Speeches (lectures)
      - "Colonial", 1877 (Box 19)
      - "How Shall Boston Keep Her Art?", 1877 (Box 19)
      - "The Growth of American Art under Rushin's Influence", 1877 (Box 19)
      - "Israel Putnam", 1877 (Box 19)
      - Untitled, 1857 (Box 19)
    - Verses
      - Miscellaneous, 1905-1917 (Box 19)
      - "Choralcelo" (Box 19)
      - "Forty Fourth" (Box 19)
      - "Our Infant's Death" (Box 19)
      - "Temperance Poem" (Box 19)
      - "Transition", 1848 (Box 19)
      - Untitled, 1850-1910 (Box 19)
  - Cobb, Emma Lillie
    - Poem on the birth of her niece, 1879 (Box 20)
    - One Foot on the Ground, 1932; reviews (Box 20)
  - Cobb, Eunice Waite
    - Speech, 1853 (Box 20)
    - Poems, 1870 (Box 20)
  - Cobb, Laura Lillie
    - "Bustings Island", 1912 (Box 20)
    - "When the Cat's Away the Mice will Play" (Box 20)
    - "A Memory", poem (Box 20)
    - Valentine and miscellaneous poems, 1866-1900 (Box 20)
  - Cobb, Percival B.
    - The Son of Man, 1916 (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous research material and notes, 1910-1955 (Box 20)
    - On creating mass culture (Box 20)
    - On education and culture in America (Box 20)
    - On growing home culture (Box 20)
    - Ideas for editorials (Box 20)
  - Cobb, Stanwood
    - Notes from interview with Abdul Baha, 1908 (Box 20)
    - On reading and culture, notes, research material (Box 20)
    - On religion, notes, research material (Box 20)
    - On Sylvanus C. (Jr. and Sr.), notes, research material (Box 20)
    - Youth group studying Baha'i, 1935; notes, research material (Box 20)
    - Arguments, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 20)
    - Articles,preliminary plays, outlines
      - Untitled (Box 20)
      - "Abdul Baha in America", 1963; articles, preliminary plays, outlines (Box 20)
      - "Advice to Parents", articles, preliminary plays, outlines (Box 20)
      - Aims and organization of the Progressive Education Association, miscellaneous fragments (Box 20)
      - "America's Lofty Nesting", 1938; article (Box 20)
      - "Art and Morality", 1905; article (Box 20)
      - "Bahai Education", article (Box 21)
      - "Bahai Education in the Future World", 1962 (Box 21)
      - "Bahai Ideals of Education", unpublished (Box 21)
      - "The Bahai Magazine", 1932 (Box 21)
      - "The Biological Aspects of Education" (Box 21)
      - "The Brotherhood of East and West", 1912 (Box 21)
      - "Canoeing on the Charles River", includes untitled fragments (Box 21)
      - "A Chance for Every Child", 1928 (Box 21)
      - "Character in Handwriting" (Box 21)
      - "The Chevy Chase Country Day School", 1926 (Box 21)
      - "Christ in the Early Church", 1908 (Box 21)
      - "Civilization of the Celestial Empire" (Box 21)
      - "The Civilization that is America", 1925; unpublished (Box 21)
      - "The Classroom Opens a Market", 1930 (Box 21)
      - "A Coaching Town in Devan and Cornwall" (Box 21)
      - "The Continuity of Religion", 1936 (Box 21)
      - "On Creating World Peace and Unity" (Box 21)
      - "Creative Expression in the Arts" (Box 21)
      - "The Decision of Fabe", 1900 (Box 21)
      - "Defects of the American novel", 1904-1907 (Box 21)
      - "The Difficulties of the Young Party", 1912 (Box 21)
      - "The Early History of the Progressive Education Association", 1920 (Box 21)
      - "Educating for Tomorrow", 1920 (Box 21)
      - "On Education" (Box 21)
      - "The Education System if the Bahai World State" (Box 21)
      - "On Education's Role in Character Development" (Box 21)
      - "An Eskimo Artist", 1936; unpublished (Box 21)
      - "The Eternal Battle Between the Romanticists and the Classicists" (Box 21)
      - "On Europe", 1912-1913; for the Newton Times; 2 folders (Box 21)
      - "On Europe", 1912-1913; for the Newton Times, unpublished (Box 22)
      - "On Travels in Europe", 1912-1913; for the Newton Times, unpublished (Box 22)
      - "The Founding and Early Organization of the Progressive Education Association" (Box 22)
      - "The Future of Education" (Box 22)
      - "The Future of World Civilization", in Spanish (Box 22)
      - "The Gift of the Fairies", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "Goals to be Reached" (Box 22)
      - "The Growth of the Short Story", 1906 (Box 22)
      - "High School", 1920; rough outline (Box 22)
      - "History of the Progressive Movement in the U.S.", 1920 (Box 22)
      - "Homoculture" (Box 22)
      - "How to Loaf and Succeed", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "How to Think", notes, research material (Box 22)
      - "The Inferiority Complex: Its Causes and Cure" (Box 22)
      - "Influence of Bahai Movement in East Bahais, and the New Woman Movement: Social and Economic Aspects of the Bahai Movement", 1912 (Box 22)
      - "Intuition" (Box 22)
      - "Is Your Child a Genius?", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "Knowledge is my Audience", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "A Land Debarred to Women", in Harper's Bazaar (Box 22)
      - "The Law of Change", unpublished (Box 22)
      - "Life and Death" (Box 22)
      - "Life and its Problems" (Box 22)
      - "Life of Bret Harte", 1902 (Box 22)
      - "Life is Interesting", proposed column (Box 22)
      - "The Lord's Prayer", 1906 (Box 22)